<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ruth Franklin&#39;s Artistic Touch</title>
    <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ruth Franklin&#39;s Artistic Touch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Artistic Touch Publications, Ruth E. Franklin</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bonnaz Embroidery</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/bonnaz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/bonnaz/</guid>
      <description>Ruth Franklin covers everything from machine operation, troubleshooting machine problems, industry professionalism to pricing embroidery work.
Every page contains details regarding bonnaz embroidery and comes with the authority and experience of a 40+ year veteran. It is highly recommended that all chain stitch operators have a printed copy of this book to reference.
When digitizing the original documents, extra effort was taken to allow for searchable keywords and phrase matches. For example, locating the section on Cornely looper timing or troubleshooting inconsistent stitch issues can be found by searching &amp;ldquo;looper&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;timing&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruth Franklin&#39;s Instructional Videos</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/educationalvhs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/educationalvhs/</guid>
      <description>The Artistic Touch School of Embroidery Videos give all of the information needed to learn to operate a chain stitch embroidery machine.
Volume 1 includes Ruth Franklin instructing her student Leah through the embroidery operation basics. Volumes 2 and 3 include Ruth Franklin demonstrating more advanced techniques. All together they cover everything that was taught to her students in person.
The full 4 hours of instructional videos can be found below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruth Script (Chainstitch Font)</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/chainstitchfont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/chainstitchfont/</guid>
      <description>“Ruth Script” is a beautiful hand-lettered script font created for chainstitch embroidery. The font is inspired by the “Artistic Script” alphabet designed by Ruth Franklin. I used her original alphabet as reference and updated it with extended characters and two variants for even more versaility beyond embroidery.
Purchasing directly supports the cost of hosting this website as well as the many hours that went into making the font available from Ruth&amp;rsquo;s original material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Artistic Touch Lettering Book</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/lettering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/lettering/</guid>
      <description>The Lettering Book contains lettering styles, placement, templating examples, and clip art all accumulated by Ruth during her 40yrs of running an embroidery art business.
Volume 3 of her VHS tape series gives a tutorial on how to embroider designs directly from this very lettering book.
The archival scan of this lettering book allows for search terms on your phone or computer and is meant to be printed for manual layouts of lettering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Embroidered Emblems</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/emblems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/emblems/</guid>
      <description>The third book in Ruth&amp;rsquo;s embroidery business publications is 74 pages long and teaches how to expertly apply chenille/moss embroidery.
The book is full of award letters, mascots and satin stitch examples and Ruth gives a small tutorial on how to recreate each and every sample. She even gives a tutorial on how she embroidered the Indian chief found on Ray Price&amp;rsquo;s custom suit that Ruth embroidered when she worked for Nudie Cohn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Monogram Design Book</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/monogramdesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/monogramdesign/</guid>
      <description>The Monogram Design Book is 277 pages and covers monograms on the Singer 114w103 but is applicable to all universal feed bonnaz chain stitch embroidery machines.
This book goes over the basics of monogram application, sizing, and pricing. It also contains a few hundred design examples and alphabets to reference.
Volume 3 of her VHS tape series gives a tutorial on how to embroider designs directly from the monogram book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cording, Braid &amp; Special Machines</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/specialmachines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/specialmachines/</guid>
      <description>The Cording, Braid &amp;amp; Special Machines Book is 122 pages long and covers the unique functionalities of the specialty Cornely machines. Ruth overviews the first-hand knowledge that she acquired from two French gentlemen who claimed to have been taught by Antoine Bonnaz himself.
This book gives an overview of the functionalities of the five Cornely machines types categorized as follows:
Group 1: Basic Universal Feed Machines. &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;AB&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;A2&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;AH2&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;E&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;LE&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;LEG&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;LEGB&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;BCH&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ACH&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;LCH&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;LGCH&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;RE&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;K&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;KB&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;LB&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;LG&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;LGB&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;LT&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;LTG&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;N&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;X.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>This site is maintained by Noah Johnson of Stitch-Rite Embroidery Service
The materials on this website were scanned and curated to be a free reference for the bonnaz embroidery community. All of the Artistic Touch publications found here are still under copyright. Please feel free to download and print any of the documents for your personal use only.
The books were scanned at an archival quality resolution and processed to be text searchable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonnie Williams</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/bonniewilliams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/bonniewilliams/</guid>
      <description>Trained By Ruth Franklin This site would not be possible without the generosity of Bonnie Williams and her 40 years of dedicated work in the embroidery industry. Bonnie met Ruth Franklin in 1979 and spent time learning to operate the Singer 114w103 bonnaz machine under Ruth&amp;rsquo;s supervision. A full machine disassembly, hours of embroidering squares to learn how to get sharp corners, Ruth ensured that Bonnie would become a skilled operator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruth Script Licensing</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/licensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/licensing/</guid>
      <description>The license purchased allows for the font to be used exclusively by a single company.
If you have any questions or need help figuring out if the license is right for you or your company, don’t hesitate to get in touch via email: noah@stitch-rite.com.
FULL LICENSE END USER LICENSE AGREEMENT
Standard Stitch-Rite | Noah Johnson Design End User Font Software License
PLEASE READ CAREFULLY this document is a legal agreement; you should print a copy for your records.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
