<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ruth Franklin&#39;s Artistic Touch</title>
    <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ruth Franklin&#39;s Artistic Touch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Artistic Touch Publications, Ruth E. Franklin</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bonnaz Embroidery</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/bonnaz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/bonnaz/</guid>
      <description>Ruth Franklin covers everything from machine operation, troubleshooting machine problems, industry professionalism to pricing embroidery work. Every page contains details regardling bonnaz embroidery and comes with the authority and experience of a 40+ year veteran. It is highly recommended that all chain stitch operators to have a printed copy of this book to reference.
Extra effort when digitizing the original documents was taken to also allow for searching the pdf for keywords and phrase matches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruth Franklin&#39;s Instructional Video</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/educationalvhs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/educationalvhs/</guid>
      <description>The Artistic Touch School of Embroidery Video is designed to give the viewer all of the information needed to learn to operate a chain stitch embroidery machine. The video is a recording of Ruth Franklin herself and covers everything that was taught to her students in person.
The full 2hr instructional video can be found in it&amp;rsquo;s original quality below. It&amp;rsquo;s accompanying transcript is available for download as well.
   High Resolution PDF #the-canvas {border: 1px solid black;direction: ltr;width: 100%;height: auto;}#paginator{text-align: center;margin-bottom: 10px;}PreviousNext&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Page:  / window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Artistic Touch Lettering Book</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/lettering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/lettering/</guid>
      <description>The Lettering Book contains lettering styles, placement, templating examples and clip art all accumulated by Ruth during her 40yrs of running an embroidery art business.
High Resolution PDF #the-canvas {border: 1px solid black;direction: ltr;width: 100%;height: auto;}#paginator{text-align: center;margin-bottom: 10px;}PreviousNext&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Page:  / window.onload = function() {var url = &#34;https:\/\/www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com\/&#34; + &#39;\/pdf\/LetteringBook_Reduced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Monogram Design Book</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/monogramdesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/monogramdesign/</guid>
      <description>The Monogram Design Book is 277 pages and covers monograms on the Singer 114w103 chain stitch embroidery machine. Ruth goes over the basics of monogram application, sizing and pricing. It also contains a few hundred design examples and alphabets to reference.
High Resolution PDF #the-canvas {border: 1px solid black;direction: ltr;width: 100%;height: auto;}#paginator{text-align: center;margin-bottom: 10px;}PreviousNext&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Page:  / window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>This site is maintained by Noah Johnson of Stitch-Rite Embroidery Service
The pdf documents were all scanned at a very high resolution and processed to be searchable via text input. For example, searching &amp;ldquo;looper&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;timing&amp;rdquo; should get you close to the areas of interest that Ruth covers.
The materials and content on this website were scanned and curated to be free reference for the bonnaz embroidery community. All of the Artistic Touch publications found here are still under copyright.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonnie Williams</title>
      <link>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/bonniewilliams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ruthfranklinbonnaz.com/posts/bonniewilliams/</guid>
      <description>Trained By Ruth Franklin This site would not be possible without the generosity of Bonnie Williams and her 40 years of dedicated work in the embroidery industry. Bonnie met Ruth Franklin in 1979 and spent time learning to operate the Singer 114w103 bonnaz machine under Ruth&amp;rsquo;s supervision. A full machine dissasembly, hours of embroidering squares to learn how to get sharp corners, Ruth ensured that Bonnie would become a skilled operator.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
